Finding Aid for Sarah Van Hoosen Jones papers, 1898-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Sarah Van Hoosen Jones papers 1898-1972
Jones, Sarah Van Hoosen.
1 linear foot
851589 Aa 2
Stony Creek and Rochester, Michigan, farmer and cattle breeder; president of the Association of Governing Boards of State Universities and Allied Institutions and member of the Committee for the White House Conference on Education. Professional and family correspondence, including letters from her mother, Alice Van Hoosen Jones, relating to everyday life, particularly in the period, 1900-1930.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dr. Sarah Van Hoosen Jones (donor no. 4427 )
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Sarah Van Hoosen Jones was born June 23, 1892 on the family farm at Stony Creek near Rochester, Michigan. She went on to the University of Chicago where she majored in languages and then to the University of Wisconsin where she earned a doctorate in animal genetics. She returned to the farm where she operated an animal husbandry business, specializing in chickens, cattle, and milk production. Her farm was for many years noted for one of the best herds of Holstein-Frisian cattle in the Midwest.
Sarah Van Hoosen Jones had a lifelong interest in Michigan State University serving on the State Board of Agriculture, the governing board of the university from 1944 through 1955. In addition, she was for many years the MSU representative on the Association of Governing Bodies of State Universities and Allied Institutions. She served as president of the Association in 1955. In 1956, she donated her farm to Michigan State University. She died in August 1972.
The collection includes correspondence and other papers regarding Jones' professional activities, the operation of her farm and cattle business, and to family matters.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Michigan--Oakland County.; Association of Governing Boards of State Universities and Allied Institutions.; Farmers--Michigan--Oakland County.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; Rochester (Mich.); Stony Creek (Oakland County, Mich.); White House Conference on Education (1955: Washington, D.C.); Women civic leaders--Michigan--Oakland County.; Women in agriculture--Michigan--Oakland County.; Civic leaders--Michigan--Oakland County.; Michigan--Social life and customs--20th century.
Contributors:
Jones, Alice Van Hoosen, 1855-1950.; Van Hoosen, Bertha, 1863-
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1898-1900 (Box 1)
  - 1901-1910 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1912 (Box 1)
  - 1913 (Box 1)
  - 1914 (Box 1)
  - 1915 (Box 1)
  - 1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917 (Box 1)
  - 1918 (Box 1)
  - 1919-1920 (Box 1)
  - 1921-1923 (Box 1)
  - 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926-1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941-1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951 (Box 1)
  - 1952 (Box 1)
  - 1953-1955 (Box 1)
  - 1956-1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961-1970 (Box 1)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Other papers
  - Association of Governing Boards
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
    - Other papers, 1954-1955, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Committee for the White House Conference on Education, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and obituaries (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)